As we have this moment of adjustment
in our Sunday pattern at church,
what are some of the things
that you think will help?
Well, I'm gonna go to 80,000 feet.
Yeah.
Very overarching.
Uh, every member of this church
has an individual responsibility to study
and learn the doctrine of Christ, and then
strive to apply it in their lives.
We cannot expect the Church
as an institution to provide
to us everything that we need to know.
There's a price that each of us has to pay
in terms of individual study.
So we go to worship the Father
in the name of the Son,
we go to participate in the ordinance
of the sacrament, and we go to learn.
I think we can characterize the change
in the meeting schedule
in a series of very simple questions.
When I was a boy, young man,
you would go to church on Sunday,
you would come home,
and the discussion question would be,
"What did you learn at church today?"
I think that world is gone, to a degree.
Mm-hmm.
I think now we return home from church,
and what did you share at church
today that you learned during the week?
Hmm.
So we study daily, we study personally,
we do that all during the week,
and then on Sunday,
we have the opportunity
to counsel together
about what we are learning.
So I think it all speaks
to home-centered, church-supported,
and ongoing opportunities
to learn for ourself.
When you think of preparing
for the sacrament meeting,
anything stand out, anything particularly
important in, in our preparation?
Yes.
We can always retain
a remission of our sins.
Mm-hmm.
I think many members of the Church,
uh, believe that when
we're baptized, we are cleansed,
and that if we mess up,
we've blown our chance.
We have the opportunity as we evaluate
our lives, reflect, repent,
prepare. The ordinance of the sacrament,
the eating of the bread and the water,
does not remit sins.
And some members think that.
Mm-hmm.
So as we consider
our preparation to participate
in the ordinance of the sacrament
and our repentance,
that's how we access the blessings
of the Savior's atoning sacrifice.
Yes.
He's our Savior
because He saves us from sin.
He redeems us from death.
But as we repent,
He forgives us. The repentance
is a necessary step,
but it is the Lord Jesus Christ
who forgives us of those sins.
It really is Him. What do we say to those
who, who accept that conceptually,
but think, "Oh, but not my sin"?
I would invite that person
to read in 3 Nephi 11-
Mm-hmm
.. where the Savior invites
2,500 people to come forth one by one
to feel the wounds in His hands,
His feet, and in His side.
And as you read that,
just ask yourself
the question, "Am I a one?"
Because you are. Whoever may think, "No,
that doesn't apply to me,"
that demonstration at the temple
in the land of Bountiful
is the essence of Him.
That's who He is. He doesn't deal
with congregations, He deals with ones,
and every single soul is a one.
Really beautiful, and I think
of how that should make us feel
and the joy we should feel from that.
This makes me think of the Lord's
intercessory prayer recorded by John
in John 17, "And now come I to thee,
and these things I speak in the world,
that they might have my joy fulfilled
in themselves." Oh, my goodness,
shouldn't every sacrament meeting
reflect this desire of the Lord's heart
and His intercession?
I'm so grateful.
There are places in the Doctrine
and Covenants where the Savior will say,
"Thy sins are forgiven."
And you read that and you go,
"Oh, I wish that could happen to me."
And the answer is,
it can, on an ongoing basis.
Yeah.
You know, we think about
attending meetings in church.
This is not about attending meetings.
This is about spiritual renewal-
Yeah
.. and growth.
Yeah. What I like to think of as getting
a fresh start, the process of,
of feeling renewed and,
and feeling new again,
and feeling forgiven.
And if what we're describing is making
sense, who would wanna miss this?
It's not, "Uh, am I going
to sacrament meeting today?"
Who would miss this opportunity
to receive these remarkable blessings?
No one, if we can create that climate.
So Elder Kearon, uh, the guidelines say
we have a 60-minute sacrament meeting,
and then a very brief time of five minutes
to make it to our next, uh,
transition.
Any thoughts, any counsel,
uh, any instruction that you would give?
I think it's a good opportunity
to help us focus on our Father in heaven
and Savior, to be very deliberate
about that as we plan and as we act
and as we practice in sacrament
meeting and in these classes and quorums.
It does say up to 60 minutes.
I don't think that means
that we're looking
for a really curtailed
sacrament meeting at all.
I think that means up to 60 minutes.
And when we think about that,
let it be wonderful.
Let us practice and experience
this until it is wonderful and beautiful.
Let the singing be transformed.
Let us choose hymns that people
can sing in a key that they can sing.
And let us have a tempo that encourages us
to sing energetically.
Let us pray and remember
our Savior Jesus Christ.
Let every talk be focused on Jesus Christ
or every experience be connected
with our faith and so on,
right from the welcome
to the closing prayer.
So if we come asking, seeking, knocking,
we will always find edification
in a sacrament meeting.
It’s true. And I’ve learned
in terms of that acting
that one of the things we can do
is very keenly listen to the people
who are speaking and praying,
to very keenly listen to them.
That involves, for me,
looking at them and actively
thinking about what they're saying
at the time they're saying it
and being sensitive to any impressions
that I'm feeling at the time.
I think that's one of the things you
might mean by acting in that situation.
Yeah. And there's a responsibility
on those
who are organizing sacrament meetings,
the bishopric, the branch presidency,
so that they help people
understand that the focus is
on the doctrine of Christ,
the Father's plan,
the Savior's role in the Father's plan,
other gospel principles
that would be appropriately articulated.
That doesn't just happen.
That has to be created.
It does.
It doesn't just pop out of nowhere.
No.
I thrill at the thought
of us feeling the love of God
and of Jesus Christ every Sabbath day,
particularly in our sacrament hour
and also in our classes and quorums.
I thrill at the thought of us
focusing more deliberately,
more keenly on our Savior Jesus Christ
and understanding His role
at the heart of our Father
in Heaven's plan of happiness.
I pray that you'll be blessed
as you experience this,
as you experiment with this,
and that you'll feel
great love and great joy
and bring your friends to feel
the same every Sabbath day.
In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.
Amen. Brothers and sisters,
we're grateful to be able
to spend this few minutes with you.
I've lived long enough to remember
when I attended primary on a Wednesday.
On Sunday, we attended Sunday
school and priesthood in the morning.
We would go home. We would come back
to the church later in the day
for sacrament meeting.
I remember the adjustments
that were made in the 1980s.
This ongoing adjustment
is a part of addressing the needs
of the church all across the globe.
So change is the essence of the gospel.
Repentance is change.
Learning is change. This is an opportunity
for us to continue to improve
and grow in how we use
the time on the Sabbath day
when we gather as Latter-day Saints.
I joyfully declare my witness that God,
the Eternal Father, is our Father,
and He lives. He is the author
of the plan of happiness.
Jesus Christ is His beloved
and only begotten Son,
and He fulfilled the atoning and redeeming
role in the Father's plan.
I witness that these things are true,
and I promise that as we use our time
as individuals and families to study
and learn the gospel, and when
we gather together on the Sabbath day,
the doctrine of Christ will distill
upon our souls as the dews from heaven,
and we will have enduring joy.
In the sacred name
of the Lord Jesus Christ, amen.